<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Sydney Crypto Seminar Series - Events</title><link href="https://hanwen-feng.github.io/cryptoseminars/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://hanwen-feng.github.io/cryptoseminars/feeds/events.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://hanwen-feng.github.io/cryptoseminars/</id><updated>2022-12-20T00:00:00+11:00</updated><subtitle>Feature Most Exciting Progress in Cryptography &amp; Blockchain</subtitle><entry><title>End-to-Same-End Encryption</title><link href="https://hanwen-feng.github.io/cryptoseminars/end-to-same-end-encryption.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-12-20T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2022-12-20T00:00:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Crypt-BC-Lab</name></author><id>tag:hanwen-feng.github.io,2022-12-20:/cryptoseminars/end-to-same-end-encryption.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="slide" src="https://hanwen-feng.github.io/cryptoseminars/images/e2se.png" title="talkslide"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spekaer:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://alkistang.github.io/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr.Qiang Tang&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  is currently a Senior Lecturer at the School of Compuuter Science at USYD doing research on cryptography and blockchain. From 2016-2021, he was an assistant professor at New Jersey Institute of Tech in the US and Director of JD-NJIT-ISCAS Joint Blockchain Lab. Before join NJIT, he was a postdoc at Cornell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; Monday 4:00 ~ 6:00 pm, 20 Dec 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; J12 Lecture Theatre, 1 Cleveland St, Darlington NSW 2008 OR Via &lt;a href="https://zoom.us"&gt;ZOOM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; The cloud has become pervasive, and we ask: how can we protect cloud data against the cloud itself? For messaging Apps, facilitating user-to-user private communication via a cloud server, security has been formulated and solved efficiently via End-to-End encryption, building on existing channels between end-users via servers (i.e., exploiting TLS, certificates, and encryption, without the need to program new primitives). However, the analogous problem for Apps employing servers for storing and retrieving end-user data privately, solving the analogous "privacy from the server itself" (cloud-blind storage) where (1) based on existing messaging/infrastructure and (2) allowing user mobility, is, in fact, still open. Existing proposals, like password protected secret sharing (PPSS), target end-to-same-end encryption of storage, but need new protocols, whereas …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="slide" src="https://hanwen-feng.github.io/cryptoseminars/images/e2se.png" title="talkslide"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spekaer:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://alkistang.github.io/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr.Qiang Tang&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  is currently a Senior Lecturer at the School of Compuuter Science at USYD doing research on cryptography and blockchain. From 2016-2021, he was an assistant professor at New Jersey Institute of Tech in the US and Director of JD-NJIT-ISCAS Joint Blockchain Lab. Before join NJIT, he was a postdoc at Cornell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; Monday 4:00 ~ 6:00 pm, 20 Dec 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; J12 Lecture Theatre, 1 Cleveland St, Darlington NSW 2008 OR Via &lt;a href="https://zoom.us"&gt;ZOOM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; The cloud has become pervasive, and we ask: how can we protect cloud data against the cloud itself? For messaging Apps, facilitating user-to-user private communication via a cloud server, security has been formulated and solved efficiently via End-to-End encryption, building on existing channels between end-users via servers (i.e., exploiting TLS, certificates, and encryption, without the need to program new primitives). However, the analogous problem for Apps employing servers for storing and retrieving end-user data privately, solving the analogous "privacy from the server itself" (cloud-blind storage) where (1) based on existing messaging/infrastructure and (2) allowing user mobility, is, in fact, still open. Existing proposals, like password protected secret sharing (PPSS), target end-to-same-end encryption of storage, but need new protocols, whereas most popular commercial cloud storage services are not programmable. Namely, they lack the simplicity needed for being portable over any cloud storage service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we propose a novel system for storing private data in the cloud storage with the help of a key server (necessary given the requirements). In our system, the user data will be secure from any of: the cloud server, the key server, or any illegitimate users, while the authenticated user can access the data on any devices just via a correct passphrase. The most attractive feature of our system is that it does not require the cloud storage server to support any newly programmable operations, except the existing client login and the data storing. Moreover, our system is simply built on top of the existing App password login system, so the user only needs one passphrase to login the App and access his secure storage. The security of our protocol, in turn, is proved under our rigorous models, and the efficiency is further demonstrated by real-world network experiments over Amazon S3. We remark that a very preliminary variant, based on our principles, was deployed by Snapchat in their My Eyes Only module, serving hundreds of millions of users!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Papers:&lt;/strong&gt; Chen, Long, et al. "{End-to-Same-End} Encryption: Modularly Augmenting an App with an Efficient, Portable, and Blind Cloud Storage." 31st USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX Security 22). 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Events"></category><category term="Computer Security"></category></entry><entry><title>Asynchronous Consensus As Fast As Pipelined BFT</title><link href="https://hanwen-feng.github.io/cryptoseminars/asynchronous-consensus-as-fast-as-pipelined-bft.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-12-19T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2022-12-19T00:00:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Crypt-BC-Lab</name></author><id>tag:hanwen-feng.github.io,2022-12-19:/cryptoseminars/asynchronous-consensus-as-fast-as-pipelined-bft.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spekaer:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://alkistang.github.io/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr.Qiang Tang&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt="Title" src="https://hanwen-feng.github.io/cryptoseminars/images/qiangTwitter.png#float-right" title="camera icon"&gt; is currently a Senior Lecturer at the School of Compuuter Science at USYD doing research on cryptography and blockchain. From 2016-2021, he was an assistant professor at New Jersey Institute of Tech in the US and Director of JD-NJIT-ISCAS Joint Blockchain Lab. Before join NJIT, he was a postdoc at Cornell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; An urgent demand of deploying BFT consensus over the Internet is raised for implementing blockchain services. The deterministic (partial) synchronous protocols can be simple and fast in good network conditions, but are subject to denial-of-service when synchrony assumption fails. Asynchronous protocols, on the contrary, are robust against the adversarial network, but are substantially more complicated and slower for the inherent use of randomness. We present Bolt-Dumbo Transformer (BDT), a generic framework for practical optimistic asynchronous atomic broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; Monday 4:00 ~ 6:00 pm, 19 Dec 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; J12 Lecture Theatre, 1 Cleveland St, Darlington NSW 2008 OR Via &lt;a href="https://zoom.us"&gt;ZOOM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Papers:&lt;/strong&gt; Lu, Yuan, Zhenliang Lu, and Qiang Tang. "Bolt-dumbo transformer: Asynchronous consensus as fast as the pipelined bft." Proceedings of the 2022 ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security. 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Events"></category><category term="Blockchain"></category></entry></feed>